homemade-gifts-made-easy.com 2018-12-29

# Privacy Policy

At Homemade-Gifts-Made-Easy.com we are dedicated to protecting your data and privacy. 

We recognize that your privacy is important. This document outlines the types of personal information we receive and collect when you use Homemade-Gifts-Made-Easy.com, as well as some of the steps we take to safeguard information. This will help you make an informed decision about sharing personal information with us. 

Homemade-Gifts-Made-Easy.com strives to maintain the highest standards of decency, fairness and integrity in all our operations. Likewise, we are dedicated to protecting our customers' and online visitors' privacy on our website. 

## About Our Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that Homemade-Gifts-Made-Easy.com stores on your computer, which your browser provides to Homemade-Gifts-Made-Easy.com each time you return to the site. We use cookies to help us identify and track visitors, their use of our website, and their website access preferences. 

### Google Analytics Cookies

Homemade-Gifts-Made-Easy.com uses Google Analytics to analyze the use of this website. Google Analytics collects demographic and interest data, and generates statistical and other information about website use, by means of cookies. These cookies are kept on your computer. We share this information with Google, which will store and use this information on its servers. Google's privacy policy is available at: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>. 

Homemade-Gifts-Made-Easy.com uses information from Google Analytics to track the number of visits to the website, browsers and operating systems. No personally identifiable information is obtained from these cookies. We use the information that Google Analytics generates relating to our website to create reports about the use of the site. These reports allow us to update the site and improve your usage of it. 

If you do not wish your data to be collected via Google Analytics, you can install its opt-out browser extension or add-on: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>

### Advertising Cookies

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our website: 

  * Google Adsense
  * Infolinks
  * Mediavine

These companies use cookies and web beacons in their ads to ascertain how many times you've seen an advertisement. We share this information with these companies, but do not provide them with any personally identifiable information for cookie or web beacon use, so they cannot personally identify you with that information from our website. 

You may opt out of personalized ads for over 125 different ad networks. [Click here to do that.](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/)

Some third-party advertisements are served by Google. Google's cookie enables it to serve ads to our visitors based on their visits to other sites on the Web. You may opt out of personalized ads by visiting the [Google ad opt-out page](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated). 

[This link from Google provides more information about how Google manages data in its ad products.](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites)

Homemade Gifts Made Easy is a participant in the Infolinks contextual advertising program. Infolinks ads appearing on pages are marked by double underlines, and hovering the mouse over the link will display more information about each ad. You may view the infolinks privacy policy [here](https://www.infolinks.com/privacy-policy/). 

Homemade Gifts Made Easy uses Mediavine to manage third-party advertising on the Website. Mediavine serves content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use cookies. Mediavine may collect IP addresses and location to serve personalized ads. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices to opt-in or opt-out of this data collection, please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

### Affiliate Products and Services

We receive an affiliate commission for some of the products and services sold on Homemade-Gifts-Made-Easy.com. 

The affiliate services platforms we use are: Amazon. 

By clicking on a product or service link, you consent to that platform's use of cookies, as outlined in the link below. 

Further detail: Homemade Gifts Made Easy is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to amazon.com. If you click on their ad or text link and buy something, we earn a small commission. If you prefer not to do this you can also go to Amazon and buy direct through them in which case we would not receive a commission. Either way the product will cost you the same amount. 

### Retargeting Ads and Tracking Pixels

Homemade-Gifts-Made-Easy.com uses retargeting ads, which require the setting of cookies in your browser. 

Homemade-Gifts-Made-Easy.com uses Facebook pixels to determine the effectiveness of some Facebook ad campaigns. You can change your Facebook ad settings [here](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=ad_settings_screen). 

### Other cookies

Some pages on Homemade-Gifts-Made-Easy.com use the Crazy Egg service to perform anonymous user tracking, and a cookie is set as part of this service. We use the information collected from this tracking to improve the usability of the web pages. No personally identifiable information is collected by Crazy Egg. If you wish to opt out of tracking then please follow the instructions on the [Crazy Egg opt-out page](https://www.crazyegg.com/opt-out). 

We use [Hotjar](http://www.hotjar.com/) in order to better understand our users' needs and to optimize this service and experience. Hotjar is a technology service that helps us better understand our users experience (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don't like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users' behavior and their devices (in particular device's IP address (captured and stored only in anonymized form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display our website). Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymized user profile. Neither Hotjar nor we will ever use this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user. For further details, please see Hotjar's privacy policy by clicking on [this link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy). 

You can opt-out to the creation of a user profile, Hotjar's storing of data about your usage of our site and Hotjar's use of tracking cookies on other websites by following this [opt-out link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out). 

### Refusing Cookies

You can set your browser to accept or refuse all cookies automatically, or notify you when a cookie is being requested. Taking this action should not cause a problem with the continued use of our site. Consult the Help section of your browser for guidance on how to refuse all cookies or to notify you when a cookie is requested. 

If you choose to refuse Homemade-Gifts-Made-Easy.com's cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the site. 

###  Site Search 

The search box on this web site ("Search Box") is powered by Google Inc ("Google"). You acknowledge and agree that Google's privacy policy (located at [ http://www.google.com/privacy.html ](http://www.google.com/privacy.html) ) shall apply to your use of the Search Box and by using the Search Box you consent to Google using your personal data in accordance with its privacy policy. 

## Personally Identifiable Information

Homemade-Gifts-Made-Easy.com may collect and use your personal information for the following purposes: 

  * To run and operate our site.
  * To display content on the site correctly.
  * To improve customer service.
  * To help us respond to your customer service requests and support needs more efficiently.
  * To personalize your user experience.
  * To understand how our users as a group use the services and resources provided on our site.
  * To improve our site.
  * To improve our products and services.
  * To run a promotion, contest, survey or other site feature.
  * To send information to you that you agreed to receive about topics we think will be of interest to you.
  * To send periodic emails, which may include electronic newsletters and/or autoresponder series of emails.
  * To respond to your enquiries, questions, and/or other requests.

Homemade-Gifts-Made-Easy.com may collect personally identifiable information from you in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when you visit our site, register on the site, or fill out a form, and in connection with other activities, services, features or resources we make available on our site. 

Specifically, if you subscribe to our newsletter, we will ask for your first name and will require your email address. 

If you complete a form, we will require your name and your email address, and will ask for information relevant to the purpose of the form. 

If you submit content to us, we will ask for your name and email address. Photos you include with your submission, or details in your submission, may personally identify you. 

If you request to be notified about comments on any content you submit to us, or request to be notified when others submit content, we will require your first name and your email address. 

If you purchase a product or service from us, we will collect your name, email address, billing address and credit card number. 

This site lets you share content with your friends and followers on various social media platforms. Below are links to the privacy policies of the platforms. 

Homemade-Gifts-Made-Easy.com also uses Facebook commenting. Facebook stores all of your comments and may show them on your timeline, depending on your Facebook settings. 

You can always refuse to supply personally identifiable information and visit our site anonymously. However, it may prevent you from engaging in certain site-related activities. 

If we make material changes in the collection of personally identifiable information, we will inform you by placing a notice on our site. We will use personal information received from you for internal purposes only and will not sell it or provide it to third parties. 

We also collect each visitor's IP address, which helps us combat spam and fraud. If you purchase a product from us and request customer support then we may also use your IP address to look up information relating to your purchase so that we can provide personalised support. We do not use IP addresses for any other purpose. 

Homemade-Gifts-Made-Easy.com contains links to other websites that may be of interest to you. However, once you have used them to leave our site, we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information you provide while visiting such sites. These sites are not governed by this privacy statement. Always exercise caution by reviewing the privacy statement of the website in question before continuing to use it. 

## Non-personally Identifiable Information

We may collect non-personally identifiable information about you whenever you interact with our site. Non-personally identifiable information may include the browser name, the type of computer and technical information about your method of connecting to our site, such as the operating system and the Internet service provider you used, and other similar information. 

## Children's Privacy Protection

This website is directed to adults. It is not directed to children under the age of 16. We operate our site in compliance with current regulations. Anyone under the age of 16 must provide parental consent to use this site. We do not knowingly collect or use personally identifiable information from anyone under 16 years of age. 

## Release of Information

If we sell Homemade-Gifts-Made-Easy.com, the information we have obtained from you through your voluntary participation in our site may transfer to the new owner as a part of the sale so that the service provided to you may continue. In that event, you will receive notice through our website of that change in control and practices, and we will make reasonable efforts to ensure that the purchaser honors any opt-out requests you might make. 

## Data Storage

Personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information collected by this site is stored on our host's servers. That host is SiteSell Inc., located at 1000 Saint-Jean Boulevard, Suite 702, Pointe-Claire, QC H9R 5P1 Canada. 

Some of the interactive features on Homemade-Gifts-Made-Easy.com are hosted on Digital Ocean. You can read the Digital Ocean privacy policy [here](https://www.digitalocean.com/help/privacy/). 

Some information is collected by third-party services. The privacy policies for these services are described linked below. 

## How You Can Correct or Remove Information

We provide this privacy policy as a statement to you of our commitment to protect your personally identifiable information. If you have submitted personally identifiable information through our website and would like to download and review that information, [click on this link](https://www.homemade-gifts-made-easy.com/gdpr-review-uyoh.html). 

You can also request to edit or delete any of your information from the servers by [clicking on this link](https://www.homemade-gifts-made-easy.com/gdpr-request-uyoh.html). 

## Updates and Effective Date

Homemade-Gifts-Made-Easy.com reserves the right to make changes in this policy. If there is a material change in our cookie and privacy practices, we will indicate on our site that those practices have changed and provide a link to the updated privacy policy. We encourage you to periodically review this policy so that you will know what information we collect and how we use it. 

## Agreeing to Terms

If you do not agree to Homemade-Gifts-Made-Easy.com's privacy policy as posted here on this website, please do not consent to the setting of cookies and the collection and storage of your personally identifiable information. 

Your explicit consent indicates acceptance of this privacy policy in its entirety. 

_Last updated: 31 May 2018_

See also: [Homemade-Gifts-Made-Easy.com Terms of Use](http://localhost:3000/disclaimer.html)
